# Irtiza Babar

Full Stack Web Developer

Full Stack Developer experienced in both front— & back—end web development. I specialize in creating user—friendly designs that are optimized for SEO and accessibility with close attention to detail, providing a friendly experience for the user.

I not only design and develop websites but also regularly test them to maintain their performance and fix any issues that arise. I also prioritize clean and organized code to make sure that it's easy to read and maintain.

Here are some sites i have developed:

https://toofiftytoo.com

https://thestyleversa.com

https://theluxeblog.com

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# **Digitano LLC**, Full Stack Developer

JAN 2024 - PRESENT

- Led a complete Refactoring of a legacy laravel codebase to improve performance, readability, and maintainability.
- Collaborated with Designers and developers to create high-quality responsive websites.
- Created Admin Dashboard for managing site.
- Constantly check for application responsiveness and eliminate bugs. As well as using linters/formatters to keep code manageable.

### JB, Full Stack Developer

FEB 2023 - NOV 2023

- Developed and maintained code for in-house web applications.
- Created designs and layouts for applications and web pages.
- Debug and fix existing software bugs to improve user experience
  & performance.

## **JB**, Frontend Web Designer(Internship)

OCT 2022 - FEB 2023

During the internship I gained experience in creating appealing and

Karachi, Pakistan +92 3079802673 irtizababar@outlook.com <u>Github (irtiza90)</u> Irtiza Babar (personal site)

#### **SKILLS**

PHP

Laravel

Python

HTML/CSS

SCSS

Bootstrap

JavaScript

React

**JQuery** 

Databases

Git / Github

API Development

user-friendly interfaces.

My work included converting design ideas into functional web pages using HTML, CSS/SCSS, and JavaScript/JQuery. My focus was in creating visually appealing, responsive websites optimized for UX and cross-browser compatibility to provide a friendly experience for users.

I also worked in optimizing website performance by implementing best practices for front-end development, such as image optimization and code minification.

Overall, the internship provided me with skills in frontend web design, and a solid understanding of UI/UX principles.

#### **EDUCATION**

**Aptech,** Higher Diploma in Software Engineering Present

The Spirit School, Metric

2022